[Music]
what time is it it's just after 8:00 oh
no don't worry Oh turn it good you look
terrific
now tell me about this date will you
have a nice little table for two I think
Charlie is also asking two of his
friends the more the merrier
what will you eat it's an Indian
restaurant I'll probably order a curry
delicious I adore Indian cooking do you
do you recommend I try anything special
why don't you try a biryani what does a
biryani exactly it's a fabulous rice
dish it's a bit similar to your Spanish
paella that sounds good mm-hmm and will
you have something to drink
I'd like some wine tonight do you like
white or red wine it depends on the
curry very sensible no don't drink too
much no no I won't I'll only have one or
two glasses oh I'm nervous for the time
don't be nervous about the time you have
loads of time
let's see Oh My heavens 8:10 I'm going
to be late no you're not
I will call the very nice minicab and he
will be here in no time
hello yes good evening yes this is
Agatha Johnson here fine thank you how
are you
glad to hear it yes can you send one of
your best drivers that's right
chess Worth Gardens number 7 ask him to
ring the bell
how long will it be ok thanks
good evening how long will it be she
says the cab will be here in five
minutes
you look like a model
Thanks how much do you think the cab
fare will be probably around 10 quid
quit don't pounce oh you have enough
money with you
yes thanks sir oh there he is now
okay bye see you night-night have a good
time Harold
oh I miss you
[Music]
hi Here I am what are you doing
ah you're having a drink can I have one
too hmm maybe it would be better to have
one after our lesson today we are going
to talk about countable nouns such as
glasses bottles and uncountable nouns
like wine champagne rice bread water
then we will see how we can use the word
some with uncountable nouns and any in
negative sentences I like to bake a cake
I need eggs flour sugar some milk oh I
don't have any butter hmm lastly we will
see how to ask what time it is and how
to answer what time is it it's lesson
time in this episode Eleanor is getting
ready to go out for dinner with friends
and she says I'll only have one or two
glasses glass
table dish are countable nouns a
countable noun is a noun that has both a
plural and a singular form 1 glass two
glasses one dish two dishes other nouns
are uncountable uncountable nouns do not
refer to individual objects and cannot
recount it wine rice water money time
uncountable nouns are always singular
and we need to use the word sum I'd like
someone you have some money in
interrogative and negative sentences we
put any where the word sum was I don't
have any money
Eleanor doesn't have any time okay
is that clear I hope so let's move on to
something different at the beginning of
this episode
Eleanor asks Agatha what time is it
do you remember what Agatha answers
right it's just after 8:00 you can say
what time is it
what's the time or could you tell me the
time the easiest way to tell the time is
by simply giving the hour and then the
minutes it's 8:00 10:00 it's 9:30
it's 10:45 but you can say also it's 10
past 8:00 it's half past 9:00 it's a
quarter to 11:00 can you tell me what
time it is now we can use a clock after
the number but only when it is the exact
hour you can say 2 o'clock 5 o'clock and
so on
the train arrives at 9:15 a.m. the
restaurant opens at 7:30 p.m.
do you know what AM and PM mean Wow
you are clever AM is anti meridian and
PM is post meridian so AM and PM tell us
whether it's morning afternoon or
evening by the way or what time is it
Oh help I have an appointment with Dylan
and I am going to be late
bye and see you soon at last you had a
long sleep yes what's the time it's
almost 12:30 it is so nice to sleep yes
and what about last night
tell me everything they were four of us
John his friend Jerry and the jealous
girlfriend Kate
oh it's Kate nice yes she's very nice
very funny
she's at nursing school oh how old is
she she is 20 and what about your dinner
I like Indian food it is ready how do
you say this is spicy yes
Indian food can be hot and spicy and we
had some white wine from Kent white wine
with gas sparkling wine oh yes England
does have some very good sparkling wine
Terry and Kate only speak English that's
good practice for you yes but it's very
difficult and very tiring well you see
we have coffee I need to ask your
opinion about something yes
Harold says I should get a job too you
want a job well it gets lonely here
during the day Victor and you or both at
school you have a fun job at the video
store oh you want to work at the video
store - no I want to work as a
salesperson selling accessories and
clothes oh you're good at that you think
so yes when you work in a boutique no
I'd like to work in a big store a
department store Oh see I'm a good
shopper I think I'll be a good seller -
you will be excellent help me practice
my sales pitch before you leave for work
and before Victor gets home what time
does Victor get home
he should be back around 6:00 okay this
is the company I'm going to apply to
Churchill's they sell very nice women's
clothing and I should get a big discount
myself can I help you madam
oh nothing I'm just looking why don't
you try on this dress it suits you hmm
it is a pretty dress but it's too big Oh
madam we have it in smaller sizes do you
have it in another color it comes in
blue green and pink how much is it madam
it's on sale it's only 42 pounds hmm
okay I'll take it very good choice madam
see you're a natural salesperson I'm
going to apply at Churchill's tomorrow
oh but hey don't say anything to Victor
no I won't I want to surprise him okay
[Music]
hi there good to see you do you like
shopping we can go shopping together but
first let's learn some English okay
today we are talking about the verb to
like and it's negative and interrogative
forms do you like shopping Agatha likes
it but Victor doesn't like it after that
we will see the comparison of adjectives
this fork is smaller than the other ones
then we will talk about prices and how
to ask for a price finally you will
learn about clothing and colors we are
starting with the verb to light in this
episode Eleanor wakes up late Sunday
morning after her night out and tells
Agatha about her dinner can you remember
what Eleanor says about the food I like
Indian food I like you like he/she/it
likes we like and so on in English too
like is very much like the verb to love
so you can say I like sparkling wine and
I love sparkling wine do you like
sparkling wine this is the interrogative
form does Eleanor like her friends do
they like shopping does Agatha like
staying at home no she doesn't
so the negative form is I don't like you
don't like he she it doesn't like we
don't like and so on for next time you
could make a list of what you like and
what you don't
okay Agatha tells Eleanor she'd like to
find a job in a department store
so they practice being customer and
salesperson Ilana says
that's a pretty dress but it's too big
and Agatha answers we have smaller sizes
do you know what smaller is right
it's a comparative adjective with
comparatives it's very simple we just
add an ER a of the adjective smaller
bigger shorter longer and so on I can
also say this is the smallest fort this
is a superlative right with the
superlative we add an est esthe at the
end of the adjective smallest biggest
longest but this is true only for all
short one syllable adjectives with
longer multi syllable adjectives there's
a difference let's see some examples
difficult more difficult the most
difficult and expensive more expensive
the most expensive since we are going
shopping as we said at the beginning of
our lesson you have to learn how to ask
about prices how much is this dress how
much is it how much are those shoes how
much are they you can also say how much
does it cost
and how much do they cost if you want to
buy some clothes you will have to ask
about size and color - do you have a
smaller or bigger size what colors do
you have do you have green do you have
blue
it's late their shops are closing soon
bye and see you next time
[Music]
hello oh how are your classes good thank
you how is your art school oh it's okay
I had a test today a test a test in art
history that's interesting what about me
what about my day Oh Aggie dear how was
your day
Betty take you shopping no actually no
shopping no shopping what on earth
happened I got a job where when doing
what how when do you start I start the
day after tomorrow I'm working ten til
five Monday to Friday congratulations
mr. James is my supervisor very nice man
a real gentleman
where are you working Churchill's off
st. James Park I'm a sales assistant in
the ladies Department well that's handy
you can take the Circle Line does Harold
know it was his idea
is this a permanent job I'm working over
the Christmas period they need more
staff mr. James says perhaps I can stay
on after the holidays good Oh what are
your plans for the holidays Alena will
you spend Christmas with us
yes please Oh Leela I'd love to but my
classes finish on the 21st I have
Christmas Day and Boxing Day off I'll
cook a turkey that he's very kind but
night return ticket is for the 23rd it
just seems so soon dear
perhaps the weather will be bad London
is famous for its fog maybe your flight
home
be delayed or or canceled they could
close the airport you simply can't go
Agatha
Elena's here for eight weeks I'm not
going yet well we'll see Victor what
about your classes we finish up this
year on December 21st after my final
exams what day of the week is New Year's
Eve
it's Monday this year oh it's so sad
everything ends let's take a photo of
Elena mm-hmm Oh Elena and Victor
together Oh Agatha smile there can I
take a photo of you are the top oh dear
no oh please okay hi nice to see you
again today we are going to learn a lot
of interesting things so sit down take a
pen and some paper and let's start oh
but before we start I'd like to tell you
the latest news I need a new swimming
costume why do you need a new swimming
costume Gabrielle because I'm going to
Miami yes I'm so excited I'm going there
by plane oh I hope the flight is not
delayed is there anybody who would like
to come with me well I guess there are
many of you who would like to go to
Miami but back to the lesson and what
I've just said is going to be very
helpful
first we'll study the verb to need and
its negative and interrogative forms
after that we'll talk about
transportation problems and when you use
Y and because then we'll look at two
expressions there
is and there are and they're
interrogative and negative forms finally
we'll learn the names of some public
holidays such as Christmas Day Boxing
Day and New Year's Day and some useful
expressions related to time in this
episode Agatha tells Victor and Elinor
that she is taken on a job as a sales
assistant then Agatha asks Elena if she
will stay with him during the Christmas
holidays but Elinor is going back to
Spain on December 23rd talking about her
new job Agatha says they need more staff
so let's talk now about the verb to need
do you remember when Elinor needs to
leave she needs to leave on the 23rd I
need you need he/she/it needs we need
etc to need means to require to want
something very much I need a new
swimming costume do you need my help
no thank you I don't need it these are
the negative and interrogative forms do
you need does he or she need no I don't
need you don't need he doesn't need she
doesn't need etc as you have seen Ellen
is going back to Spain perfect you are
brilliant
unfortunately when travelling there may
be problems why is the flight delayed
because of the fog why is the train
delayed because of a strike so we use
the word y for the question and because
for the answer why do you study English
because it's useful and fun at least I
hope so why do you need a new swimming
costume Gabrielle because I'm going to
Miami let's look at the two expressions
I mentioned earlier there is
there are for example there is a book on
the table there are some books on the
table now the interrogative form
are there any classes is there enough
time you can answer
there aren't any classes and there isn't
any time this is the negative form right
to finish the lesson in this episode
Agatha said they need more staff for the
Christmas period so let's look at some
public holidays Christmas Day Boxing Day
December 26 New Year's Day Easter Sunday
Independence Day even though I'm an
adult my favorite holiday
still is Christmas and yours hmm
time to go but bye and see you soon